# 張凱鵬 (ZHANG, KAIPENG)

Tel: (86) 18817957729

E-mail: kp\_zhang@foxmail.com

Homepage: http://kpzhang93.github.io/

#### **About Me**

I received my M.S. degree at Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia, National Taiwan University in 2018. His supervisor was Prof. Wins. Before that, he received his B.E. degrees in 2016 from Donghua University. I also did research internship at Microsoft Research Asia, Tencent AI Lab and MMLAB of CUHK at Shenzhen.

My research interest mainly lies in computer vision, deep learning, and face analysis. I totally got more than 700 *citations* and 2000 *Github stars*.



#### **Education**

## **National Taiwan University**

09/2016 - 08/2018

M.S. in Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia, supervised by Prof. Winston Hsu.

• GPA: 4.1/4.3

#### Donghua University, Shanghai

09/2012 - 06/2016

B.Eng. in Computer Network Engineering (Excellent Class)

• GPA: 87/100

#### **Experience**

#### Visual Computing Group, Microsoft Research Asia

01/2018 - 07/2018

Research Intern

Mentor: Dr. Dong Chen

### • Large-scale face recognition

Tencent AI Lab 07/2017 - 09/2017

Research Intern

Mentor: Dr. Zhifeng Li and Dr. Wei Liu

#### • Real-time face detection and alignment

#### 09/2016 - 08/2018

## **National Taiwan University**

Master student & Research assistant

Adviser: Prof. Winston Hsu

## • Low-resolution face hallucination and recognition

Accepted by ECCV 2018

## Disguised Faces in the Wild

1st winner of Disguised Faces in the Wild Challenge, CVPR 2018.

#### Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination

Accepted by CVPRW 2018

## Using two-stream contextual CNN with inside cascaded structure for fast and accurate face detection Accepted by ICCV 2017

#### Group-level emotion recognition in the wild

1st winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge

Multimedia Laboratory, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology

• 2<sup>nd</sup> winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge

07/2015 - 08/2016

Visiting student

Adviser: Prof. Zhifeng Li and Prof. Yu Qiao

- Face Recognition using proposed discriminative deep feature learning approach.
   Accepted by ECCV 2016
- Joint face detection and alignment using multi-task cascaded convolutional networks
   Accept by IEEE SPL
- Facial gender, smile and accessories classification using deep convolutional neural networks 1st winner of ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge Track 2 & 3, CVPR 2016.

## Publications (2 ECCV, 1 ICCV, 3 CVPRW, 2 ICMI, 1 SPL)

- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Chia-Wen Cheng, Winston Hsu, Yu Qiao, Wei Liu and Tong Zhang, "Super-Identity Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", *ECCV*, 2018.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Ya-Liang Chang and Winston Hsu, "Deep Disguised Faces Recognition", CVPRW, 2018.
- Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Jianfei Yang, Debin Meng, Kaipeng Zhang, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Cascade Attention Networks For Group Emotion Recognition with Face, Body and Image Cues", ICMI Grand Challenge, 2018.
- Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee, Chia-Wen Cheng and Winston Hsu, "Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", *CVPRW*, 2018.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Hao Wang, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao and Wei Liu, "Detecting Faces Using Inside Cascaded Contextual CNN", *ICCV*, 2017.
- Lianzhi Tan, Kaipeng Zhang, Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Group Emotion Recognition with Individual Facial Emotion CNNs and Global Image Based CNNs", ICMI Grand Challenge, 2017.
- Yandong Wen, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Discriminative Deep Feature Learning Approach for Face Recognition", *ECCV*, 2016.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "Joint Face Detection and Alignment using Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks", *IEEE SPL*, vol. 23, no. 10, pp. 1499-1503, 2016.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Lianzhi Tan, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks", *CVPRW*, 2016.

#### **Selected Honors & Awards**

Disguised Faces in the Wild Workshop, CVPR 2018	2018
• 1 <sup>st</sup> winner	2016
Group-level emotion recognition, Emotion Recognition in the Wild, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge  ● 2 <sup>nd</sup> winner	2018
Group-level emotion recognition, Emotion Recognition in the Wild, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge  ■ 1 <sup>st</sup> winner	2017
Accessories Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016  ■ 1 <sup>st</sup> winner	2016
Smile and Gender Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016  ■ 1 <sup>st</sup> winner	2016
Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis	2016

### **Academic Service**

Reviewer of ACCV 2018, CVPR 2018, TNNLS, Neurocomputing, and SPL